"The Spirit Integrates You" 4th Public Programme
靈將我們整合 ＂奧地利維也納
September 30th, 1982, Urania, Vienna, Austria
第四次公開講座 1982年9月30日
I bow to all the seekers of truth.
我向所有追求真理的人致敬
In my last lectures
在之前的講座
I’ve been telling you about these centers
我告訴了你們
which are placed in the lower part of the body.
位於下半身的能量中心
Today I would like to cover the rest of the three centers
今天我想講述其餘三個
which lie here, here and here.
在這兒、這兒和這兒的能量中心
These are very important centers for human beings.
這些能量中心對人類都很重要
When man as a human being raised his head up,
當人類抬起頭
this center established a new dimension.
這個被稱為喉輪的能量中心
This center is called as Vishuddhi chakra.
建立了一個新的空間向度
And this has got sixteen petals
它有十六塊花瓣
which manifests in the sympathetic or
彰顯在我們的交感神經
the para-sympathetic nervous system
和副交感神經系統
sixteen plexuses,
十六個神經叢
which looks after our eyes, nose, throat,
照顧我們的眼睛、鼻子、喉嚨
and our tongue,
和舌頭
our eyes, part of the eyes,
我們的眼睛、部分眼睛
and the whole expression of the face.
和整個面部的表情
When man is ego-oriented, he puts back his head like that.
當人是自我取向，他會像這樣仰起頭
And when he’s super-ego-oriented,
當他是超我取向
he puts down his head like that.
他就會像這樣垂下頭
This center is extremely important for human beings
這個能量中心對人類
and for Sahaja Yoga,
對霎哈嘉瑜伽都是極之重要
because the hands play a big part in Sahaja Yoga.
因為雙手在霎哈嘉瑜伽扮演著重大的角色
To get a universal language we have to use our hands -
用手來表達是宇宙的語言
that is the best, for say, for people who are blind,
這種表達方法是最好的。就如盲人
who are deaf and dumb, best thing for them is
聾啞的人，對他們來說
to use the hands.
最好用雙手
So these hands, though we express ourselves by moving
雖然我們移動
fingers and gestures, are still not enlightened.
手指和用手勢來表達自己，但我們的雙手卻仍未得到啟發
When this center gets enlightened
當這個能量中心獲得啟發
then these hands become enlightened, too.
我們的雙手也受到啟發
This center has two sides,
這個能量中心有兩邊
one on the right and one on the left.
一是在右，一是在左
The left-side center is caught up when a person feels guilty
當人感到內疚，左邊的能量中心便會有阻塞
and obstructs the ascent of the Kundalini.
阻礙靈量的上昇
That’s why I always request all the Western seekers first
因此我經常要求西方的求道者
to say in their hearts, “Mother, I’m not guilty.”
先在心裡說：「母親，我並無內疚感。」
These are the conditionings that have come to us
我們這些思想制約，是來自
from so-called religions,
所謂的宗教
from so-called psychologists,
所謂心理學家
and other people who are responsible for our development
和一些我們年幼時
in our childhood.
照顧我們的人
When material things were very important for the parents,
當父母對物質性的東西很着緊
they all the time shout at children or correct them, saying
時常向孩子大叫或糾正他們，說：
that, “Don’t spoil the carpet, don’t spoil that,
「別弄髒毯子，別弄髒這個
don’t spoil that.”
別弄髒那個。」
And that is how we develop a kind of a guilt within us.
內疚感就是這樣在我們心裡形成
When we grow up in the schools and colleges,
當我們在學校，在大學成長
this can be built up very heavily within us, too.
這種內疚感可以很牢固地在我們內裡形成
Education has to be imparted to children with great love
要以極大的愛心和
and understanding.
諒解去教育孩子
There’s a big feeling, especially with the people who are
一般人都有這種想法，特別是那些
very developed that children must be controlled
奉行要用洗腦的方法
by brainwashing.
去管教孩子的人
But this brainwashing results in this funny trouble called
但這種洗腦的方法卻會令孩子
guilt.
有內疚這種滑稽可笑的毛病
In the same way the psychologists who discuss
同樣，討論內疚
this subject of guilt are really not understanding the effects
這個題目的心理學家，並不了解
of this kind of a discussion.
這種討論的後果
These psychologists, when they talk about the trouble of guilt,
當這些心理學家談內疚
they do not know that these are pathological cases.
他們不知道這些是病理性的個案
This is not normal, this is abnormal case.
這是不正常的，這是不正常的個案
But if you start discussing about these abnormal cases
當你開始概括地談論這些不正常的個案
in a general way, it becomes a general disease.
它便變成一般的疾病
They themselves work with the sick people,
他們與被邪靈附體的病人
who are possessed, and they have no way of protecting
一起工作，卻沒有任何
themselves from these sick people.
保護自己的措施
That is how they themselves become sick.
這就是他們染病的原因
And then once they develop this sickness within them,
一旦他們染上這種疾病
they start generating it on a larger areas by saying that
藉着說︰人發展內疚感，這是源自內疚感
one develops a guilt, and this happens with guilt,
那是源自內疚感
that happens with guilt.
他們藉此更大範圍的去擴散這種疾病
Now God has created human beings in His own image.
神以自己的形象來創造人類
There is no need for human beings to feel guilty
人類是不用無緣無故
for nothing at all.
感到內疚
If these human judges have not been able to find you
若俗世人類的法官不能
as guilty, how can that judge, who is nothing but compassion,
判你有罪，那位充滿慈悲的法官
will brand you as guilty?
又怎會判你有罪？
You have come from amoeba to this stage,
你由亞米巴原蟲進化到這個階段
and God has created you as the epitome
神創造你為
of the whole Creation.
整個創造的縮影
And now at this stage you start feeling guilty.
你竟然在這個階段感到內疚
When He wants you to adorn the seat of your Spirit
當祂想你在這偉大的時刻
at this great moment, you are becoming guilty -
裝飾你的靈的寶座，你卻變得內疚
just very disappointing,
這是非常令人失望
the whole thing is extremely disappointing.
整件事都極之令人失望
All these evolutionary things have happened within you,
你內在的進化，
not to make you feel guilty.
不是要令你內疚
It would be like a prince who is now to be anointed
就如王子將要被加冕
as a king, suddenly stops - says that
成為國王，王子卻突然停下來說：
“Oh, I’m guilty, I can’t become the king.”
「噢，我有罪，我不能成為國王。」
Self-pity is worse than suicide.
自憐比自殺更差勁
So the right-side problem is just the opposite of left side.
右脈的問題與左脈的剛剛相反
That is a person who talks with aggressiveness,
這類人說話充滿侵略性
who has a personality that he talks in such a way that
他的個性品格是既用說話
he impresses people and puts them down.
來打動人又用說話來奚落人
Such a person develops a very harsh and a dry personality.
因此這類人形成很刻薄和枯燥乏味的個性
I know of a dentist who came to see Me. He was a dentist,
有一個牙醫來見我。他是牙醫
but he told Me, “Mother, I have lost power to smile even.
他告訴我：「母親，我失去笑的能力
I can’t smile now.
我現在不能笑
My muscles do not go into the mood of smiling at all.
我的肌肉根本沒有心情笑
I have become so feelingless that I cannot smile - nor cry.”
我變得毫無情感，我不能笑亦不能哭。」
So he went to some saint, so-called, and the saint said,
他因此去見一些聖人，所謂的聖人，聖人說：
“Oh you have gone beyond everything now.”
「噢，你現在已經超越一切。」
This is the wrong idea we have for people who are very
我們對靈性上很偉大的人
great in spirituality.
就是有這種誤解
Such a person has to be an ocean of compassion,
這些偉大的人理應是慈悲的海洋
ocean of love and ocean of forgiveness.
愛的海洋和寬恕的海洋
Above all,
除此之外
he should be able to give joy to people and not miseries.
最重要的是他應該能帶給人喜樂，而非悲傷
Normally wherever I see a painting of a saint or
通常我看到的聖人畫像或
a statue of a saint, he looks the most miserable to Me.
雕像，他們看來都是十分悲傷不快
Wherever the some artists, architects have carved the popes
一些藝術家、建築師為教宗和
and the bishops and all that, they look so miserable
主教這些人物雕刻建造雕像，雕造出來的樣子都是很悲傷
that nobody would like to take their place.
因此沒有人想接替這些人物的位置
Sometimes with these aggressive people,
有時候，這些具侵略性的人
as a result of their aggression,
因為他們的侵略性
also develop the left side because they feel guilty
亦變得左脈
the way they have talked to others.
即使是他們與別人說話所採取的態度
With this you develop problems
他們也感到內疚
both the sides of the center if they are in imbalance,
這樣你兩邊的能量中心都會出問題
you develop a center into such a way that
若能量中心不平衡，
a physical problem called spondylitis can develop.
你會患上脊椎炎
If you feel guilty or if you feel aggressive,
內疚感或富侵略性
both ways it can work out.
都能產生這種情況
Specially if you feel guilty, then also a heart problem
特別是若你感到內疚，便會患上
called angina - sort of a thing develops.
心絞痛這種心臟毛病
And also you develop a stiff left hand with that.
你的左手亦會變得僵硬
Now in short I have told you about the Vishuddhi chakra,
我已簡短地向你們介紹了喉輪
because we have to cover three chakras,
今天我要講解三個輪穴
and I want to tell you today about the Spirit.
亦想告訴你有關靈
Above that is the center of Agnya.
喉輪之上是額輪
Agnya chakra lies in the region of
額輪是位於
pituitary and pineal body.
腦垂體和松果體的區域
It is placed exactly in the center of optic chiasma.
也正正處於視覺神經叢
One of the windows of Agnya chakra is shown here
我額頭這個記號
on My forehead with this mark,
顯示額輪的其中一扇窗
and another one is at the back of the head.
另一扇是在頭的後部
Now this center is also extremely important because
這個能量中心是極之重要
it controls your ego and super-ego.
因為它控制你的自我和超我
This is the center where Jesus Christ, our Lord resides.
耶穌基督，我們的主耶穌就是住在這能量中心
Many priests have been shocked when I told them this.
很多牧師聽到我這麼說都很震驚
But His cross is symbolic of this cross where the ego and
基督的十字架是象徵自我和
super-ego cross each other and are extremely close.
超我在這兒交錯的十字架，它們極之接近
This is the place where Christ was to be placed and
這就是耶穌基督被安置
bestowed upon, and this was to be accomplished by
被賜予的位置。這是要透過祂
His crucifixion so that His subtler body enters into
被釘十字架來成就，藉此祂精微的身體
that area of our awareness.
進入我們的意識
When Christ said on the cross that,
耶穌基督在十字架上說：
“Now it has been established”  He meant to say that
「現在它已經建立鞏固。」祂說的
this accomplishment is the establishment of Christ
成就是建立鞏固耶穌基督
in that center, which is very,
在這個非常精微，非常
very subtle and difficult to enter into.
難進入的能量中心
He was, His body, only His body was made of
祂是，祂的身體，祂的身體是
the vibrations that you feel.
由你們感受到的生命能量所構成
These vibrations are called either Om or
這些生命能量在梵文被稱為
Chaitanya in Sanskrit language.
Om 或 Chaitanya
When He is just made of that, He could walk on the water.
因為祂是生命能量所構成，所以祂能在水上行走
The other day somebody told Me that Christ has been
某天有人告訴我說
born somewhere and now He is going to come on the TV.
基督在某處誕生，現在祂要上電視
So I said, “Better ask Him to walk on the water and then
我說：「最好叫祂在水上行走
you’ll find Him.”
你便能找到祂。」
Now, this establishment was important,
這個建立鞏固是很重要的
and at the time of crucifixion, when He was in that state,
在釘上十字架的一刻，當祂在那狀態
He said only one sentence, which shows that something
祂只說了一句話，這表示
was to be accomplished by His crucifixion. “It”.
某件事情要通過祂被釘上十字架來成就完成。「它」
“He didn’t say everything is accomplished -
「祂沒有說一切都成就了」
He said, “It has been accomplished.”
祂只說：「它已經成就了」
He has talked of the future about Holy Ghost, that
祂談及未來的聖靈
everything will be forgiven whatever is done to Him,
祂會寛恕因為無知而
because done in ignorance,
對祂所做的一切
but nothing against the Holy Ghost will be forgiven.
可是，祂不會寛恕違抗反對聖靈的人
He said, “I’ll send you a counselor,
祂說：「我會派一位顧問
who’ll explain everything to you.
向你們解釋一切
I will send you a redeemer, who’ll redeem you.
我會派一位拯救者，來拯救你們
And a comforter, who will give you comfort.”
還會派一位安慰者，給你們安慰。」
The third thing He has said that,
第三件祂說的是：
“You are to be born again.”
「你們要重生。」
He’s the only one who said this in the whole of Bible,
在整本聖經中，只有祂這樣說
Moses and all these people, it is He who said that,
摩西和這些人，是祂說：
“You are to be born again.”
「你們會重生。」
Because Moses, as I told you the other day, and Abraham
像我那天告訴過你，因為摩西和亞佰拉罕
were busy establishing your balance in that green part
忙於建立身體
of the body.
這個綠色部分的平衡
But this awakening of Christ within you,
只有基督說
the awakening of your power as a second birth
喚醒你內在的基督，喚醒你的力量
was only said by Christ.
就是重生
So we started giving baptism to people.
我們開始為人們施洗
You get some water from somewhere,
你委派某人為牧師
appoint somebody as a clergyman,
找點水來
put on the head of a person and say, “You are baptized.”
放在某人頭上說：「你已經受洗了。」
It is such an artificial thing
這樣做是那麼人為做作
because there is nothing that has happened,
因為什麼也沒發生
just you have put some water, anybody can do it.
你只放點水，任何人都能做到
But to get baptism, you have to raise the Kundalini
真正的洗禮是你要提昇靈量
to break through.
要突破
Christ didn’t say that, “You take water and put on
基督沒有說：「你拿點水
somebody’s head” , did He say so?
放在人們的頭上」」，祂有這樣說過嗎？
But a second birth has to take place.
第二次出生要發生
And the second birth,
第二次的出生
birth itself means an evolutionary process,
出生即是進化的過程
or you can call it a living process has to take place.
或你可說是活生生的生命過程要發生
In Sanskrit language a bird is called as Dvijaha,
梵文鳥兒被叫作Dvijaha
and a realized soul also as Dvijaha,
覺醒的靈也被叫作Dvijaha
means twice-born.
即重生
Like a bird is an egg, first of all,
像鳥兒首先是蛋
then he grows in that eggshell,
它在蛋殼裡生長
and then it matures, it breaks through,
成熟，最後破殼而出
and it comes out as a transformed personality,
鳥兒出生時個性已經轉化
as something else, absolutely something else from the egg.
變成另一種東西，絕對與蛋完全不同的另一種東西
On the Easter day we give people eggs
在復活節我們送蛋給人
to remind them that, "You are egg now and
來提醒他們，你們現在是蛋
you have to become the bird.”
你們要變成鳥兒
But I don’t think people know that,
我不認為人們了解這一點
because resurrection is the message of Christ.
因為復活是基督的訊息
Crucifixion is the accomplishment,
釘十字架是完成實現
but Resurrection is His message.
而復活則是祂的訊息
And the way we are making Christ look so miserable
我就是不能了解，為何人們
is something I just can’t understand.
令基督看來那麼悲慘哀傷
They just show the skeleton of Christ hanging
他們顯示基督皮包骨的
with a skin there -
掛在十字架上
can a skeleton carry such a big cross?
一副骨頭怎能背負那麼大的十字架？
Michelangelo was another realized soul who painted Christ
米高安哲羅是繪畫基督
like the way He was, a huge person,
如其人的覺醒的靈，基督是個巨人
person who was healthy, full of vigor and joy,
健康、充滿活力和喜樂
and not a miserable pitiable caricature.
並非悲哀可憐的漫畫角色
I think people who are sadistic enjoy this kind of a thing
我想只有虐待狂才喜愛
to see somebody miserable.
見到別人悲傷
Perhaps that is the reason because just below that I have
或許這就是原因，因為我在下面見到一副
seen a miserable looking skeleton
被視作是基督，可憐兮兮的
put there as Christ on the table.
骨頭放在桌上
Spiritual life is not misery by any chance.
靈性生活絕不悲慘
It was a thing of great pride that Christ came on this earth
基督來到世上是一件值得自豪的事
because when He’s awakened within us at this point,
因為當祂在我們內裡被喚醒
He sucks in the ego and super-ego.
祂吸掉自我和超我
That means He takes away all our conditionings and
即是祂帶走我們一切思想制約
our actions, the karmas.
我們的行動和業(karmas)
That means in the Christian words we can say
用基督徒的說法
He sucks away all our sins.
祂吸掉我們的罪
He has died for us.
祂為我們而死
He has gone through all the miseries.
祂經歷一切苦難
He didn’t leave any misery for us to go through.
沒有留下任何苦難讓我們來經歷
There is no need for anyone to be miserable now.
現在沒有人需要悲傷
For example, Jews said that, “Oh we...-
例如，猶太人說：「噢！我們...
they denied Christ and that’s how they said,
他們否定基督，因此他們說：
"Oh we must have miseries.
「噢！我們要有苦難
We have to suffer."
我們要受苦。」
So they suffered nicely.
所以他們好好地受苦
When Hitler came in, he made them suffer.
因此希特勒出現，讓他們能受苦
That’s what they were thinking was religious life, was that?
他們以為這是宗教虔敬的生活，對嗎？
And today the same people who suffered
今天，這一群曾受苦的人
have become the other side of it and they are doing all
走向另一端。他們做盡一切
kinds of things without any relation to their religion.
跟他們的宗教沒有關係的事情
Because the greatest of greatest Commandment is,
因為最重要的誡律中最重要的是：
“Thou shalt not kill” .
「你不能殺人。」
And then how do you explain this Christian militia
你如何解釋這基督徒部隊
in the name of Christ killing so many helpless people?
以基督的名義殺掉那麼多無助的人？
Small children,
小孩子
innocent small children, women, for no crime of theirs.
天真的小孩子、婦女，他們並無犯任何罪
In the name of God, in the name of Christ,
以神之名，以基督之名
in the name of Mohammed, these people are just using
以穆罕默德之名，這些人只是施展
their sadism.
他們的虐待狂
Where is the word that is said as love
那些愛心和
and compassion of God?
神的憐憫的字眼在哪裡？
Mohammed has talked of Rahamat,
穆罕默德談及Rahamat
all the time of Rahamat, he calls God Rahim.
常常談及Rahamat，他稱神為Rahim
Rahamat means compassion,
Rahamat即是慈悲
Rahim means the embodiment of compassion.
Rahim是慈悲的化身
One can’t understand these nations,
人們難以理解這些國家
what they have done of God and these incarnations,
他們對神，對降世神祇做了些什麼
nobody can explain.
沒有人能解釋
Those who followed Buddha, like Japanese and Chinese,
佛陀的追隨者，像日本人和中國人
what are they doing?
他們做著什麼？
We have some followers of Mahavira, they have become
摩訶維瓦(Mahavira)的追隨者，變成
such extreme vegetarians that they try to save mosquitoes
極端的素食者。他們甚至連街上的蚊子
and all little worms on the street.
和小蟲也想拯救
They are so stupid that they make some bugs
他們愚蠢到讓一些蟲子
to suck the blood of a realized soul
吸食覺醒的靈的血
so that the bugs will get realized.
只為讓蟲子能得到自覺
This absurd vegetarianism - one should understand
我們要知道，這種荒謬的素食主義
are we going to give Realization to chickens?
我們是否要給雞自覺？
We are more kind to animals and to our tables and chairs
我們對動物，對桌椅比對
than to our own children.
自己的孩子更仁慈
Human beings are going in the wrong direction.
人類走錯了方向
The right direction is to be in the center
正確的方向是在中央
and watch for the Last Ascent.
等待最後的昇進
And when the Kundalini rises
當靈量上昇
She takes you through this gate of Christ,
它帶你通過這道基督之門
through Him alone it takes.
通過祂是唯一的途徑
That’s why I said through Him everybody has to pass
因此我說人人都要通過祂
into the realm of Kingdom of God,
進入神的國度
which is the Limbic area within you.
那是你內在的邊緣系統
The super-ego and ego represent your past and future.
自我和超我代表你的過去和未來
A thought rises and falls off and another thought rises
一個思緒出現，離去，另一個思緒出現
and falls off.
再離去
One is a past, one is a future.
一是過去，一是將來
Our mind jumps on the cusp of these thoughts.
我們的思維遊走於思緒之間
We have to be in the center of these two thoughts,
我們要在這兩個思緒中央
which is the present, we have to be.
即現在
But just by giving lectures and saying,
單單只在演講時說：
“Now you be in the center” , you just don’t become.
「你們要在中央」，是不能達到的
By giving lectures or giving badges or starting organizations
藉着演講、派襟章、成立組織
or having some sort of a postcard with you
或張貼某些明信片
attached on your head,
在頭上
you don’t become that.
是不能達到的
All honest seekers must know that this is all outside,
所有誠實的求道者要知道，這全是外在的
it has nothing to do with inside.
與內裡毫不相干
If you are true seekers and know that all these things
若你是真正的求道者，你便知道這些
are ego-pampering,
都是縱容自我
and is very misleading.
也是十分誤導的
It is to be understood in its right perspective,
我們要以正確的觀點
in the proper wisdom of a human being.
以人類恰當的智慧去了解
Now when you cross through your Agnya chakra
當你穿越你的額輪
you become thoughtlessly aware,
便會變得無思無慮
because you establish your attention in the present.
因為你把你的注意力建立鞏固在現在
But again I have to tell you one thing
我要重申一點
that this is not a myth,
這並非人為虛構的
it is an actualization that has to take place
而是實現實踐要發生
it has to happen within you.
它要在你們內裡發生
Your awareness has to be enlightened. It is not just saying,
你的意識知覺要被啟發開悟。不是只說：
“I am an enlightened being” ,
「我是個覺醒的存在體」
giving a false certificate to yourself.
給自己發假證書
Then the Kundalini passes through the last chakra
當靈量通過頂輪這個最後的輪穴
of the Sahasrara, 1000 petals,
千塊花瓣
and opens out into the subtle energy of God,
開啟進入神的精微力量
His love and His compassion.
進入祂的愛和慈悲之中
At this time, you are thoughtlessly aware,
此時，你變得無思無慮
but you are in complete state of bliss and relaxation.
處於完全喜悅，完全放鬆的狀態
You feel the All-pervading power for the first time
透過涼風，你首次感受到
as Cool Breeze.
全能的力量
This is the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost
這是可蘭經中被描述為“Ruh”
described in the Koran as “Ruh”,
在印度經典叫作
in the Indian scriptures as Chaitanya Lahari,
”Chaitanya Lahari”的聖靈的涼風
means waves of consciousness.
即知覺的波浪
We can put waves of enlightened consciousness.
亦可說是開悟了的知覺的波浪
There are books and books written about it
很多很多用梵文寫的書籍
in Sanskrit language,
有相關的記載
but they are not translated.
但它們並沒有翻譯出來
Some people who went to India to study Sanskrit,
有些人到印度學習梵文
they were only interested in the loopholes of the culture.
他們卻只對文化的漏洞感興趣
Like a thief is interested in all the weaknesses of a bank,
就像盜賊只對銀行的漏洞感興趣
they went there to study what they can get
他們去那裡學習了解，以印證他們
to support their weaknesses.
取得的銀行弱點漏洞
In the late 6th century in our country, a big
在印度六世紀後期
revolt against God broke out as tantrism,
一場稱為性力派(tantrism)反神的大型起義發生
where insulting the deity and - unholy behavior
侮辱神祇，不神聖的行為被視為
became the signs of tantrism.
性力派的象徵
They behaved in such a manner that the -
他們的行為令神祇
with the repulsion the deities disappeared.
感到嫌惡，因而消失
And they created an area around them where they could get
他們在周圍製造了一個地帶，把一切
all the negative satanic forces to handle.
邪惡負面的力量集合，以供他們使用
This is called as in Sanskrit language as bhoota vidya,
梵文稱這為bhoota vidya(魔鬼的知識)
preta vidya and all that which in short means
preta vidya(邪惡的知識)等等，簡單地說
the knowledge of the cemetry.
即是墳墓的知識
Please don’t disturb others.
請不要騷擾他人
Now this vidya was practiced, this science was practiced
那些想誘騙催眠別人
by people who wanted to entice and hypnotize people
想賺錢的人學習運用這些知識
and make money.
這些科學
But the people who went there only studied these
到那裡的人只學習
erotic and dirty things, which has no meaning
色情和骯髒的東西，這些污穢不堪的東西
to the philosophy there.
對那裡的哲學是毫無意義
I went to Nepal twice with My daughters;
我與女兒到過尼泊爾兩次
we never saw anything wrong there.
我們沒見過有什麼不對勁
But then one of the Sahaja Yogis told Me the Nepal is filled
但有個霎哈嘉瑜伽士告訴我，尼泊爾是
with these - the erotic images.
充滿這些…色情的雕像
I said, “Where are they? I can’t see.”
我問：「它們在哪裡？我看不到。」
“See there,” he said, “on top of the temple.”
他說：「看看那兒，在廟宇的屋頂。」
All these Japanese had their zoom lenses
這些日本人都把對焦鏡頭
put up there to see it.
向着屋頂觀看
They had brought special type of ladders, you see,
他們帶來專用的梯子
special type of ladders to climb up,
用來爬高專用的梯子
to take the special photograph of the special brains.
去拍攝特別的腦袋特別的照片
And the Nepalis told Me that these stupid people
尼泊爾人告訴我，這些蠢人
are doing something so unholy and unsanctified.
在做着不神聖，神聖不可侵犯的事情
They have no sense of holiness.
他們不知何謂神聖
And I said, “that’s not so.
我說：「並非如此
They have, but they have lost it now,
他們本來有的，但現在卻失去了
they can make money out of it.”
他們可以從中賺錢。」
But they were surprised, they said,
他們感到驚訝，說：
“Who is going to buy these inauspicious things in the house?
「誰會購買這些不吉祥的東西回家？
They’ll bring all bhoots in the house.”
它們會把邪靈帶回家。」
But these tantrikas had convinced these poor artists
這些性力術士說服了可憐的藝術家
that you make such statues on top of the temple so
告訴他們把這些雕像放在廟宇的屋頂
so that the goddess of thunder is a virgin,
好使是處女的雷神…
ans she will never come near this,
不會走近這兒
because it’s so dirty, you see.
因為它是那麼骯髒，明白嗎
So, one has to understand that God is purity,
我們要明白，神是純潔
He is sanctity,
祂既聖潔
and He is Holy.
又神聖
He is Holy.
祂是神聖
Now, with this idea, now I’m going to tell you about
有了這個概念，我要告訴你們神聖
the holiest and holiest that resides within you,
你們內在的聖潔
the beauty that is within you,
內在的美
the bliss that resides within you,
內在的喜悅
and the light that watches you.
看顧着你的光
It is your Spirit.
就是你的靈
It is a reflection of God Almighty in your heart.
它是全能的神在你內心的反映
And the Holy Ghost is the power of God Almighty.
聖靈是全能的神的力量
God is the witness of the play of the Holy Ghost.
神是靜觀聖靈這齣戲劇的旁觀者
Christ’s Mother was Herself an incarnation of that,
基督的母親正是聖靈的化身
but it was not mentioned in the Bible because if these
聖經卻沒有提及這些，因為若
Romans or Jews had known that She is the One,
羅馬人和猶太人知道她就是聖靈
they would have cut Her into pieces
他們會把她碎屍萬段
and attacked Her.
攻擊她
So, it was not said because Christ had to play
沒有提及是因為基督要
this drama of crucifixion.
上演釘十字架這齣戲劇
But you can find out after your Realization
在你獲得自覺後
through your vibratory awareness that whatever I’m saying
可以通過感知能力發現我說的
about them is absolute truth.
都是絕對的真理
Because your Spirit “which is the Absolute “
因為你的靈是絕對的
gives you the absolute answers.
所以能給你絕對的答案
It doesn’t give you relative answers.
它不會給你相對的答案
It takes you out of this relative world.
它把你帶離相對的世界
And you know the absolute through your new awareness,
通過你的新感知力
which is vibratory awareness;
即是生命能量的感知
we can say the sanctified awareness, the holy awareness.
你知道絕對。我們可說是聖化的感知，神聖的感知
When this Kundalini rushes through this point,
當靈量衝上這一點
She enlightens the Spirit,
她開悟了靈
because the seat of the Spirit is here.
因為靈的寶座就在這裡
In our brain, all these seven centers are placed like this.
我們的腦袋裡，所有七個能量中心
All the seats of the centers are in the brain.
是這樣排列的，所有能量中心的寶座都在腦袋裡
So, when the Kundalini comes out of this center,
所以當靈量在這個能量中心走出來
all the centers get integrated,
所有能量中心都得到整合
because the Spirit integrates you.
因為靈把你們整合
Like in the room, when you have no light you are fighting
就像若這房間沒有燈
for different, different places, different, different things.
你便要四處摸黑
But when there is light,
當有了燈，你便知道
you know where you stand with what.
自己身處何方
So the relativity is dropped out.
因此相對性消失了
But when you become the Spirit,
當你成為靈
your attention gets enlightened
你的注意力被啟發
into collective consciousness: it becomes,
為集體意識：它成為
because this Spirit in you is the collective being.
因為你內裡的靈是集體的存在體
Everybody’s Spirit is connected with each other.
每個人的靈都互相聯繫
It gives a message which is the collective message.
它發放的訊息是集體訊息
Now when you place your hands towards yourself and try
現在，當你把手向着自己
to find out by putting your aura into a proper bondage,
為自己的能量場做保護
then you can find out about yourself.
你便能找出自己的毛病
If it is a physical and a mental imbalance, then the right
若是肉身和心理的不平衡
hand shows on the fingers different centers.
便會顯現在右手手指的不同能量中心
And when it is an emotional problem, the left hand shows.
若是情緒出問題，便顯現在左手
All these vibrations you receive there in sensations
你能解讀接收到的生命能量的感應
are decoded and you can verify everything.
亦能驗證一切
Sitting down here,
坐在這裡
you can feel the vibrations of any person.
你能感應任何人的生命能量
The other day I said that Mozart was a born realized.
某天我說莫札特是天生有自覺的人
So they said, “How do we know?”
他們說：「我們怎能知道？」
I said, “Just put your hands and think of Mozart” ,
我說：「只是張開雙手，想着莫札特」
and immediately tremendous vibrations start flowing.
立即有很強的能量在流動
When such realized souls play any music
當這些覺醒的靈彈奏音樂
or paint any paintings, for a realized personality
或繪畫圖畫，對覺醒了的人來說
it is the greatest source of joy -
這是喜樂最大的來源
because you don’t think about it.
因為你不用思考
But the essence of the creator of that joy
喜樂的創造者的精華
becomes one with yours.
與你融合合一
You feel the bliss flowing in you.
你感到極樂在你內裡流動
And you enjoy it only for joy’s sake
因為喜樂所以你享受
because Spirit is the joy within you.
因為靈是你內裡的喜樂
Spirit is the joy, means it is neither happiness or
靈是喜樂，意思是它既不是快樂
unhappiness, but it is single thing, is joy.
也不是不快樂，它單純是喜樂
Happiness comes when your ego is pampered, and
當自我被縱容，你便快樂
unhappiness comes when your super-ego suffers.
當超我受傷，你便不快樂
You get out of the duality of these two and
你擺脫這種二元性
you become the joy, which is singular,
而成為喜樂，喜樂是單一的
which is because you become the witness of the play.
因為你成為戲劇的靜觀者
No more you are in it involved.
不再牽涉其中
Supposing you are in the water,
就如你在水中
then you have the fear of the drowning,
因為你看到四周的波浪
because you see the waves around.
所以害怕會被水淹死
But supposing you get into the boat
但若你上了船
and are established; you are established in the boat
穩定了；你安坐在船上
then you enjoy the same waves.
便會享受相同的波浪
That is the mastery you have to reach.
你們就是要到達這種掌握能力
Another very gross simile I’ll give you,
我給你另一個粗淺的比喻
but don’t carry too far with your mind.
但你不要想得太多
In a car you have a brake and an accelerator.
汽車有制動器和油門
In the same way we have the accelerator and the brake.
我們同樣有制動器和油門
The human driver tries to balance both of them.
駕駛者儘量平衡兩者
Then he becomes the expert driver.
便會成為專業的司機
Then automatically he drives.
他自動地駕駛
Now the master is sitting at the back - that is the Spirit.
現在師傅坐在後面 – 即是靈
Then this expert driver becomes the master and sees
這專業的司機成為師傅
the driver in him drive.
看著內裡的司機在駕駛
Now, when you see yourself as a third person,
當你以旁觀者的身份看自己
you are not involved in the joke.
你便不會牽涉在這笑話中
You must have seen some little children talk like that
你一定見過有些小孩像這樣
in a third person.
以第三者身份來說話
Like they’ll say, “This John will not go there.”
例如他們會說：「約翰不會去那裡。」
These days there are so many realized souls born in Europe
今天有很多覺醒的靈在歐洲
and England, America that we must get Realization
英國和美國出生，所以我們要獲得自覺
to look after them.
去照顧他們
There are great saints born on this earth.
有偉大的聖人在這地球出生
They talk another language of vibratory awareness.
他們說的是能量感知這種另類語言
If they have a problem, they suck the finger to suggest.
若他們遇上問題，會以吸吮相關的手指來表示
Many saints want to be born.
很多聖者想出生
But in the countries where the children are not understood
但他們會避開那些不了解
and respected and loved, they avoid it.
不尊重，不愛護孩子的國家
All the Sahaja Yogis who are married now have got great
所有已婚的霎哈嘉瑜伽士都會
saints born to them, tremendous people.
生下偉大的聖者，了不起的人
That is how I would request you, all of you, to know that
我請你們所有人知道
the time of Resurrection has come,
復活的時候到了
the time of your judgment has come.
審判你們的時候到了
That many people who asked Me one more question
很多人時常問我同一個問題：
all the time that, “What about cleansing ourselves before
「進食前先清潔自己好嗎
coming to eat - we are not yet ready.”
我們還未準備好。」
You don’t have to judge yourself.
你不用審判自己
You have done all these things in your previous lives,
這些事情你在前世已經做過
you don’t have to do anymore now.
現在不用再做了
Apart from this, we have to know that the One who has
另外，我們要知道，這個宇宙的創造者
created this Universe is much more worried
更着緊拯救
in saving this creation.
祂的創造
All His aspects are busy there to help you out
祂的每一個向度特點都忙於幫助你們
if He has to save His creation.
若祂要拯救祂的創造物
He has to save human beings.
祂就要拯救人類
And this blossom time has come where many flowers are
開花結果的時候到了
going to become fruits.
很多花朵會成為果實
Sahaja Yoga has been there since times immemorial.
霎哈嘉瑜伽遠古已經存在
All those who got Realization got through spontaneity,
那些獲得自覺的人都是自然地得到的
there’s no other way out -
沒有其他途徑
as every seed gets germinated through its living force.
就如每一顆種子都是靠這活生生的力量發芽
But on the tree of life, there were one or two flowers
生命之樹開始時
to begin with.
只有一兩朵花朵
But today there are many flowers.
但今天卻有很多很多花朵
So it has to be an en-masse happening.
所以這是大規模的事件
Many of you who have been to India with Me have seen
你們很多人曾與我一起到印度
thousands of people getting Realization,
見過數千人獲得自覺
because in the villages there are people
因為鄉村的人
who are not so complicated.
沒有那麼複雜
And it will happen to so many people on this earth.
這也會在這個地球上很多人身上發生
A lady interviewer asked Me,
一名女訪問員問我：
“How will it go to people whom You do not meet?”
「沒有見過你的人怎樣得到自覺？」
It is very simple because when I was in Hong Kong,
很簡單，我在香港時
the lady who owned a television asked Me to stand up
電視台的女老闆叫我站起來
and give vibrations to people.
給人們生命能量
And in that horrible, busy city many people got
在這個可怕繁忙的城市，很多人通過
Realization through television.
電視得到自覺
The science has developed so many things like a camera
科學有很多發明，如照相機
which can take a photograph and which has the vibrations.
它能拍下有能量的照片
There are so many ways we can spread it much faster than
在今天，有很多方法讓我們能以
Christ could have done it, or anybody could have done it
比基督或任何人更快的途徑
in these Modern times.
傳揚散播它
But it is difficult because it is becoming.
儘管如此，要傳揚它仍是很困難，因為它變得…
People like a convenient type of a yoga.
人們喜歡方便型的瑜伽
If you tell them to stand on their heads they’re happy.
若你叫他們倒立，他們很樂意
But if you tell them just, “You have to put your hands” ,
但若你只告訴他們：「你要把手放好」
they just don’t understand.
他們就是不明白
But all the vital things of this world are done so simple,
世上一切重要的事情
in such a simple manner.
卻都是很簡單
Apart from your evolution, your breathing, your seeing,
除了你的進化，你的呼吸，你看東西之外
everything is so simple.
一切都是那麼簡單
It is so vital, so it has to be simple.
因為它很重要，所以它要簡單
So people who like to have lots of mental fits
那些要霎哈嘉瑜伽能與他們的思維有很多共通之處的人
with Sahaja Yoga find it difficult to accept.
很難接受霎哈嘉瑜伽
I do not say that you close your brains or on the contrary,
我不是說你要關閉腦袋，又或相反
open it, completely.
完全開放
Logically reach the conclusions,
要邏輯地得出結論
not blindfolded,
並非盲目的
not blind faith.
不是盲目的相信
But once you have come to logical conclusion,
一旦你得出邏輯的結論
you cannot do with this limited brain
你便不能依賴這有限的腦袋
because you have to enter into the unlimited.
因為你已經進入無限
And for that we have to leave this limited behind.
為此我們要放棄這種有限
But once you get enlightened, everything becomes logical.
一旦你得到開悟，一切都變得合情合理
You can verify everything.
你能驗證一切
It is so simple, like to the blind people,
它是很簡單，就像我們不能
we cannot tell about the colors, we can just say,
與失明人談各種顏色。我們只需說：
“All right, let the eyes open then you can see.”
「好吧，張開眼睛，你就能看見。」
And that is what is as simple as getting Self-Realization.
獲得自覺就是那麼簡單
There is no danger,
不危險
no problem.
也不會出問題
May God bless you all!
願神祝福你們！
Today is the last day,
今天是最後一天
and I thank you very much for giving Me this opportunity
非常感謝你們給我機會
to be with you all, such great seekers,
與你們一起；那麼偉大的求道者
and I’m sure next year again I’ll come.
我明年必定會再來
Even if you don’t get your Realization today,
即使你今天未獲得自覺
you will all get it, we are going to start a center here
你們全都會得到它。我們會在這裡開設一個中心
and we already have a follow-up meeting.
已有跟進的聚會
As there is no money involvement you people have to
因為是免費的
organize it yourself for Vienna, and Austria.
你們在維也納和奧地利要自己組織統籌
And it is your own look-out.
你們自己要小心
But you all can write to Me in London all your problems.
你們可以寫下你們的問題寄到倫敦給我
So, may God bless you!
願神祝福你們！
Today is the last day, and if you want,
今天是最後一天，若有需要
you can ask questions for about five minutes or so,
你們可以花五分鐘時間發問
but better is to get to Realization.
但最好還是取得自覺
You people can come here on the staircase.
你們可以來樓梯前
I think some can come down
我想一些人可以過來
because there are some more coming in.
因為還有人進來
Come this side, please.
請來這邊
Don’t stand in the door, come this side.
不要站在門前，來這邊
As I have told you that this is your own.
我說過這是你自己的
This is your own property.
是你們的資產
It’s just an enlightened light can enlighten another light.
就像燃點了的燈能點亮另一盞燈
There is no obligation of any kind.
沒有任何責任
As if on My finger is paining, and I rub it,
像我的手指痛，我擦擦它
there’s no obligation on My finger.
我的手指沒有責任
As you are not the other, there is no other for Me.
正如你們不是其他，沒有其他人能代替我
So if I am just pressing My finger and comforting it,
若我按摩手指，使它舒適一點
there’s no obligation of any kind, I better do it.
是沒有任何責任，就做吧
Now, whatever I just tell you, please listen to Me
現在，無論我告訴你們什麽，請聆聽我
and cooperate with Me, that’s all.
與我合作，就是如此
First you must know that you have to have a cheerful
首先你要知道，你要有愉快的
temperament.
性格
There is nothing to be serious about it nor to be frivolous,
沒什麼值得認真嚴肅或無聊輕挑的去對待
but be cheerful, because you are going to have
只要興高采烈，因為你們現在要獲得
the last ascent now.
最後的昇進
Now, you put your hands towards Me in a very relaxed
現在，雙手很放鬆地向着我
way, keep them on your lap, but before that
放在大腿上。但首先
you better take out your shoes,
要脫下鞋子
because they are tight and they stop
因為它們很緊
the connection with the Mother Earth.
令你不能與大地之母有任何接觸聯繫
Also you can loosen if there’s something tight in your neck
若你的頸或腰有東西束得緊
or on your waist, if there’s something very tight,
若有很緊的東西，就要把它放鬆
means you should be comfortable.
即是說你要感到舒適
Or if there is any heavy necklace or anything,
又或若有很重的頸鏈之類的
something that is weighing on the chakras -
一些壓在輪穴上的東西
because very subtle thing it is.
因為它是精微的東西
You can take out even your glasses - will be all right.
你甚至可以摘下眼鏡 – 會沒問題
Now everyone has to do it.
現在每個人都要做
Those who are not going to do it should go out.
不想做的人要離開
Everyone has to close the eyes.
大家都閉上眼睛
If somebody keeps eyes open, it disturbs the vibrations,
若有人保持眼睛張開，會影響生命能量
so I request you in the interest of everyone be civil and
因此為各人的利益着想
you better go.
我要求你離開
You have to be also kind to yourself.
你要對自己好些
Now, please close your eyes.
現在請閉上眼睛
And do not put any pressure of your attention be taken
不要放注意力
to any place. Just leave it loose.
在任何地方，只管放鬆
The concentration and all that is not to be done
完全不用把注意力
at all anywhere.
放在任何地方
Just leave your attention absolutely loose.
只管把注意力完全放鬆
Let it think, let it do what it likes.
讓它想，讓它做它喜愛的
Don’t put any pressure on it - just now.
不要有任何壓力 – 現在此刻
And now you should know that the left hand of yours
你應該知道你的左手
is the expression of your power of desire.
是代表願望的力量
And the right hand is the power of action.
右手是行動的力量
So we have to use the right hand for the action and left
我們要用右手來行動
hand is kept towards Me, little stretched out fingers.
左手向着我，輕微伸展手指
And keep your hand very relaxed.
手十分放鬆
Now, the right hand, as I’ve told you, that first we have to
現在右手，像我說過，我們首先要
get rid of this so-called guilt-business from our minds,
由腦袋拿走這所謂內疚的東西
so it should be put at the left side of your neck -
所以手要放在頸
from the front side.
前方的左邊
But don’t open your eyes and keep the left hand
但不要張開眼睛，左手保持
stretched towards Me straight -
張開向着我
but on the lap.
在大腿上
Now, by putting that you just say,
放好後說：
“Mother, I’m not guilty.”
「母親，我並無內疚感。」
Please say it again and again, “Mother, I’m not guilty.”
請重覆說：「母親，我並無內疚感。」
That is important because that is one of the big problems
這是十分重要，因為這是西方國家
in the Western countries.
其中一個大問題
Now you put your right hand on your heart.
把右手放在心上
And say,
全心
with full understanding and with your heart,
全意說：
ask a question, “Mother, am I the Spirit?”
「母親，我是否一個靈？」
Ask the question three times.
問三次
On the heart - little higher it is.
在心上 – 高一點
Heart is little higher, yes.
心是高一點的，對了
Ask a question thrice.
問三次
Because you are, but just ask a question.
因為你正是靈，只問問題
Now please put your right hand on the left side
請把右手放在
of your stomach.
腹部的左邊
And ask a question, “Mother, am I my own master?”
問：「母親，我是否自己的導師？」
Say it ten times, please.
請說十次。問：
“Am I my own guru?”  just ask.
「我是否自己的導師？」
If you have gurus or anything, if there’s any conditioning,
若你有跟隨靈性導師之類，有思想制約
that will drop out immediately
它們會馬上消失
because you are your guru.
因為你是自己的導師
You don’t need any guru at all.
你根本不需要任何導師
When you become the guru, you don’t need the guru at all.
當你成為導師，你完全不需要任何導師
So please ask with full confidence.
所有要充滿信心地問
What’s her name?
她叫什麼名字？
See, this is the negativity, what is the need?
看，這就是負面能量，為什麼需要這樣？
The wife is not going to be killed here.
在這裡，妻子不會被殺
This is how they attack, you see?
他們就是這樣作出攻擊，明白嗎？
Better go now. Tell your husband to behave himself.
走吧。叫你的丈夫要檢點
You can’t disturb, you see. Let her go away.
你不能打擾，明白嗎。讓她走吧
This is the thing, they are not civil even,
就是這樣，他們甚至不文明
they are not civil people. How can they get Realization?
他們不是文明人，怎能獲得自覺？
Very uncivil.
十分不文明
All right, doesn’t matter.
好了，沒關係
Forgive, forgive, forgive.
寬恕、寬恕、寬恕
Put your right hand again
再把右手
on the left side of your stomach and say ten times now,
放在腹部的左邊。說十次：
“Mother, I am the guru.”
「母親，我是自己的導師。」
Now say please again,
請再說：
“My only desire is to become the Spirit.
「我唯一的願望就是成為靈
my pure desire is to become the Spirit,
我的純粹願望就是成為靈
to become my own being, to become the Self,
成為自己的存在體，成為真我
to become the Absolute.
成為絕對
So let it manifest.”
讓它彰顯吧。」
Now put the right hand again on your heart
把右手再放在心上
and say, “Mother, I am the Spirit.”
說：「母親，我是一個靈。」
Say it with full confidence that you are, believe Me.
充滿信心地說你是，相信我
Put your feet straight on the Mother Earth, touching it
腳垂直放在大地之母上，垂直
straight, you see, don’t push forward your legs.
接觸着大地，你看，不要把腳向前伸
Those who are sitting on the floor are all right;
坐在地上的人沒問題
they don’t have to worry.
他們不用担心
So now on the heart you put it and say,
現在把手放在心上說：
“Mother, I am the Spirit.”
「母親，我是一個靈。」
Say it twelve times.
說十二次
Don’t feel guilty.
不要感到內疚
Please, this is the only snag you have, all of you is
這是你們唯一的障礙
that you are feeling guilty while saying it.
你們說時全都感到內疚
Be confident, I’m saying you are the Spirit.
要有信心，我是說你們是一個靈
Why do you judge yourself?
為什麼要審判自己？
Let the Divine judge you.
讓上天審判你
So just say -
只管說
without feeling guilty.
沒有內疚感
All right, without feeling guilty say that,
好了，沒有內疚的說：
“If I have done anything wrong, forgive me.”
「若我犯了任何錯，請原諒我。」
You can say this to God,
你可以對神這樣說：
“Oh God, if I have done anything wrong,
「神啊，若我犯了任何錯
please forgive me.”
請原諒我。」
Without feeling guilty,
沒有內疚感
because to take out your guilt I am just saying this.
我這樣說是為了帶走你的罪疚感
Better.
好了點
Better. Still there.
好了點。仍有一點
Now please put the right hand again on the left shoulder
現在請再把右手放在左邊肩膀
near the neck.
接近頸的地方
And again say, please again say sixteen times now,
再說，請再說十六次：
“Mother, I’m not guilty.”
「母親，我並無內疚感。」
Please say it.
請這樣說。
With no pity towards yourself, but with confidence.
不要自憐，而是充滿信心
Hm, better.
好了
Now put your right hand
現在把右手
on your forehead across and press it.
橫放在前額按着它
Press the upper line of your hand - across.
用手按着 - 橫向
And say,
說：
“Mother, I forgive everyone.”
「母親，我寬恕所有人。」
Much better.
好多了
Now put this hand on top of your head, on the fontanel
把手放在頭頂，在腦囟
bone, where it was a soft bone in your childhood,
即你小時軟骨的位置
and try to feel the thickness of your head
感覺頭的
in the central part of your head,
中部的厚度
backwards, forwards, and try to press it.
向後，向前，按着它
From the base of your hand you can press it,
你可以用手的底部按着它
Try to press it, you can do it yourself.
嘗試按着它，你可以自己做
With the base, with the base of the hand.
用手的底部，用手的底部
Now, very good.
現在，很好
Now put the hand on top and see if there is
現在把手放在頭頂，看看
cool breeze coming.
有沒有涼風出來
Now you have to say, “Mother, I want my Realization” ,
你要說：「母親，我想得到自覺」
because I cannot cross your freedom,
因為我不能干涉你們的自由
you have to ask for it.
你們要自己要求
You can change over your hand.
你可以換另一隻手
Put the right hand on your lap towards Me
把手放在大腿上向着我
and the left hand on yourself.
左手在頭上
Move it up and down to see there is cool breeze blowing.
上下移動看看有沒有涼風
You can go on changing your hand to find out.
你可以換另一隻手去試試
If there are journalists in this group,
若這裡有記者
I would request them to take their Realization,
我請他們先獲得自覺
otherwise they should not publish anything,
否則他們不應發表任何文章
because you can’t understand Sahaja Yoga without it.
因為沒有自覺，你是不能明白理解霎哈嘉瑜伽
It is not a superficial thing.
霎哈嘉瑜伽並非表面的東西
You have to get your Realization otherwise you will disturb
你們要得到自覺。否則你會擾亂
or disudale or you can say, misguide the people,
或阻礙…或你可以說，誤導其他
who are seekers.
求道者
Now, better, good. Many are getting it.
現在好一點。很多人都獲得了。
Now put your both the hands towards Me,
現在雙手向着我
and see if you are getting cool breeze.
看看有沒有涼風
In your hands, don’t open your eyes,
從你的手出來，別張開眼睛
keep your neck straight.
頸保持直
If you are feeling the cool breeze, well and good
若你感到涼風，很好
otherwise also it is perfectly alright,
感覺不到也不要緊
you please the eyes
眼睛請…
I will tell you how to rise your Kundalini, yourself.
我會告訴你們怎樣提升靈量
And now you should watch Me without thinking.
要沒有思維地看着我
Just put your hands like this.
手向着我